Of all human weaknesses, obsession is the most dangerous, and the silliest!
Mighty Aphrodite is a comedy, romance film directed by Woody Allen.
When Lenny and his wife, Amanda, adopt a baby, Lenny realizes that his son is a genius and becomes
obsessed with finding the boy's biological mother in hopes that she will be brilliant too.
But when he learns that Max's mother is Linda Ash, a kindhearted prostitute and
porn star, Lenny is determined to reform her immoral lifestyle.
A Greek chorus chimes in to relate the plot to
Greek mythology in this quirky comedy.
Lenny, played by Woody Allen.
Linda Ash, played by Mira Sorvino.
Amanda, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Chorleiter, played by F. Murray Abraham.
Amanda's Father, played by Donald Symington.
Amanda's Mother, played by Claire Bloom.
Mighty Aphrodite is a 1995 American comedy film written, directed by, and co-starring Woody
Allen, alongside Mira Sorvino, Helena Bonham Carter, Michael Rapaport, and F.
Murray Abraham.
The screenplay was vaguely inspired by the story of Pygmalion and revolves around a sportswriter named Lenny Weinrib (Allen) and his search for
his genius adopted son's biological mother, ultimately finding that she is a dim-witted prostitute named Linda Ash (Sorvino).
Critical reception of the film was generally positive, with
Sorvino earning high praise for her performance.
She won several accolades, including the Academy Award and Golden Globe Award for Best Supporting
Actress, and was nominated for the BAFTA Award and SAG Award in the same category.
Allen's screenplay earned him a nomination for the
Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay.
The film explores themes of prostitute, adoption,
adoptive father, child prodigy, childlessness.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.